http://shop.owlkids.com/pages/privacy-policy

Create an Account
Due to high volume, processing times may be longer than usual. We are making every effort to meet this high demand. We thank you for your patience and understanding.
Books
New Books
Chirp Books Series
Picture Books
Nonfiction
Fiction
Early Childhood
Character Development
Privacy Policy
At Owlkids, we understand the importance of protecting the privacy of our customers, especially children.  That is why we have created this privacy policy to address your concerns.
Our Policy
This policy applies to all information collected, mail, phone and online.
What information is collected and why?
Owlkids collects personal information (such as name, mailing address, telephone number, email address and/or credit card number) for the following purposes:
To process and mail magazine subscriptions
To process and fill product orders including print books, ebooks, single issues, slipcases, eMagazines, etc.
To mail subscription invoices and renewal notices
To mail receipts for subscriptions or other purchased products
To communicate information and promotional offers
Surveys, polls, reader submissions, and contest administration.
Why do you need the child’s date of birth?
We use this information for content research purposes. The magazines are targeted to specific age groups, Chirp 3-6; Chickadee 6-9, OWL 9-13. By providing the child’s date of birth, you are helping us to ensure that the magazine content is appropriate for the age group.
Why do you need the child’s gender?
This information is also used for content research purposes. Our goal is to make the magazines inclusive and appealing to boys and girls. By indicating that the child is a boy or girl, you are helping us to ensure that we are achieving our content goals.
How secure is your information?
The security of your personal information is very important to us!  Your information is stored in secure databases and filing systems, and we use encryption technology to protect your credit card and other payment information during transmission to prevent tampering and credit card fraud.
How are children protected?
Owlkids does not require anyone to share personal information about themselves to enjoy the games and activities on our site.
Some activities, such as E-cards and Talk About it, require email addresses for sending cards and comments.  However, these email addresses are not stored.
What about Reader Submissions?
Readers can submit artwork, opinions, and comments to us online or by mail.  We ask for the child’s first name and age, when they are submitting entries.  This information is used to credit the entry.  This information is not shared with third parties.  All submissions and entries become the property of Bayard Canada, the parent company of Owlkids.
What about Contest Entries?
When participating in a contest, readers are required to submit a completed entry form.  The information is used for contest administration and winner selection. At the time of entering the contest, contest winners (their parents or guardians) consent to use of their information including photos and/or videos for promotional or advertising purposes.
How are Letters & Emails Used?
We receive many letters and emails from our readers every day.  We encourage children under the age of 13 to ask a parent’s permission before sending a correspondence.  When possible, letters and emails will be answered by one of our staff members, usually in the form of a “thank you for writing” letter.
What about your eCommerce Sites?
The ecommerce sections of our website(s) are intended for use by visitors 18 years of age and older.
How are Cookies used?
We use both temporary and persistent cookies on our sites.  Temporary session cookies are specific to the current visit and help to remember information from that visit such as items in your shopping cart and calculate shopping cart totals.  Session cookies expire when you close your browser.  Persistent cookies are used to give you access to your account and edit your profile, language settings etc.  Another type of cookie is used to give us information about our website.  This cookie does not obtain any personal information about you or provide us with any way to contact you, and it does not extract any information from your computer.  We use it to track site traffic such as identify pages and items that get the greatest interest, create the most problems etc. This helps us with overall site evaluation and information for provide a better experience for you.
What are Marketing Preferences?
We want to communicate with you in ways that you prefer such as newsletters, special offers, new product announcements, contest, surveys and celebrations. To communicate with you, we use a consent standard, either express or implied.  Express consent occurs when you have told us that you want to receive promotional and informational emails from us.  Implied consent allows us to contact you because you are a customer.  You can withdraw your consent at any time by clicking the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of an email message or by contacting us by phone or email.
Do you rent your Mailing List?
From time to time we make our mailing list available to carefully screened companies (adults only). If you would like to be excluded from these mailings please contact us at 1-800-551-6957.
Questions or concerns?
If you have any questions or concerns about our Privacy Policy, you can contact us at:
Email: privacyofficer@owlkids.com, Subject: Attention Privacy Officer
Telephone:  416-340-2700 (9 a.m.-5 p.m. Eastern Time, Monday through Friday)
Effective: November 2016
